Ilya Pivavaruk

Henderson, NV • (702) 815-5133 1ilya1gray@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/ilya-pivavaruk-04bb78182/

Software Developer/Engineer

Driven, versatile graduate with Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and initial programming and testing experience in the software development industry. A capable team player skilled in quality assurance and testing game design and troubleshooting programming issues. A researcher with a passion for applying the latest augmented reality technology to real world products and applications. Poised to excel in the software development, game development, and robotics industries. Portfolio available at https://ilyapivavaruk.github.io/

Computer Science/Engineering

- Experienced in building servers and apps required for server communication.
- Conducted research using the latest augmented reality technology.

Communications

- Effectively communicate with diverse groups in a variety of settings to keep team members apprised of progress and encourage feedback and cooperation.
- Equally able to operate within a team environment or independently and keep stakeholders apprised of project status and problems as they arise.

Software Development

- Supported quality assurance and security testing for video game development in the mobile device market.
- Assisted in developing apps to make them available on Google Play and Apple App Store.

Training

- Has provided professional instruction and tutoring to students ages 7 to 18.
- Facilitated customized instruction on topics including software development, web development, robotics, and video game development.

Technical Proficiencies

Programming (Proficient): C#, C++. (Basic Knowledge): Java, Python, HTML/CSS, Autolt, MIPS, x86-64

Languages: Assembly, React

Programming Git Technologies, data structures, and algorithms.

Skills:

Software: .NET Framework, Eclipse, NetBeans, Unity3D, UnrealEngine4, Visual Studio, Office 365

Platforms: Windows, Linux, Mac OS

Professional Experience

University of Nevada, Las Vegas (UNLV), Las Vegas, NV Augmented Reality Researcher/Engineer

May 2021 - Current

Conduct research on the latest augmented reality technology. Used C# and Unity3D coupled with AR Foundation libraries to construct indoor navigation application for both Android and IOS. Built server using Python and constructed app for server communication.

 Developed AR Navigation app, an indoor navigation system to allow students to navigate buildings to locate classrooms, labs, and instructor offices on the UNLV campus. The app is available for both Android and IOS systems. App constructed during summer 2021, published in August 2021, and is still being updated by myself and used daily by students.

Code Central, Las Vegas, NV Programming Instructor

Taught and tutored students from ages 7 to 18 on both a one-on-one basis and in group settings of 5 or more. Rather than a formal curriculum, instruction was based on students' interests in the following areas: software development (C++, C#, Python, Java), web development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript), robotics (Raspberry Pi based with Python), and video game development (Unity with C# and Unreal Engine with C++ and blueprints).

 Customized coursework tailored to students' needs and interests, requiring flexibility to quickly study and master topics in order to teach effectively.

Scary Robot, Las Vegas, NV Technical Advisor

Jan. 2019 - Mar. 2019

Provided quality assurance and security testing for a company that creates video games for mobile devices. The primary project was a game called Volley Village. Included on game credits along with the development team.

Assisted in the development of the game Volley Village, available on Google Play and Apple App Store.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (Dean's List recipient with 3.96 GPA, Graduation May 2022) University of Nevada, Las Vegas, Las Vegas, NV

Coursework includes:

Analysis of Algorithms, Machine Learning, Data Structures, Computer Science, Programming Methodology, Web Development, Robotics, Discrete Mathematics, Computer Organization, Compiler Construction, Honors Calculus

Volunteer Experience

Rebel Game Devs club UNLV, Treasurer and Founder, 2018-2019

Languages

Russian, fluent Belarussian, basic Ukrainian, basic Polish, basic Spanish, basic